Guide to the Frick Fine Arts Library Subject Files, 1939-1989 FFAL.001
ULS Frick Fine Arts Library
- Frick, Helen Clay, 160; Chiefly newspaper articles. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 160)
  Item Listing: "Helen Clay Frick dies at Point Breeze Estate", November 10, 1984, Pittsburgh Post Gazette. "Helen Clay Frick dies at 96", November 10, 1984, Pittsburgh Post Gazette. ""Frick & Pittsburgh", February 16, 1967, Pittsburgh Catholic. "Defender of a Memory: Helen Clay Frick", May 26, 1967, The New York Times. "History of Frick Upheld in Court", May 26, 1967, The New York Times, "Defamation: Victory for Historians", June 2, 1967, Time Magazine. "Lawyers Defends Frick Litigation", September 21, 1966, The Pitt News "Stevens' Lawyer Attacks Frick Editorial", November 2, 1966, The Pitt News. "Frick Author Discusses Trial", October 3, 1966, The Pitt News. "Miss Frick Loses Book Libel Suit" "Frick's Attorney Clarifies Stand", February 24, 1967, The Pitt News. "Miss Frick Loses Suit Over Book", May 26, 1967, Pittsburgh Press. "2-Year-Old Frick Case Up to Judge", January 12, 1967, Pittsburgh Post-Gazette. "Editorial: The Frick Scylla & Charybdis", October 5, 1966, The Pitt News. "Miss Frick's Lawyer Discusses Litigation; Attacks Stevens' Book", October 5, 1966, The Pitt News. "Frick's Daughter Sues Historian Over Appraisal", July 5, 1966, The New York Times. "Judge Upholds Book About Frick", May 26, 1967, Pittsburgh Post Gazette. "Profiles: Daughter of her Father - I", July 15, 1939, The New Yorker. "Profiles: Daughter of her Father - II", Jusy 22, 1939, The New Yorker. The Frick Collection [New York], Brochure. Photocopy of original plaque inscriptions for library. "Filial Piety and the First Amendment" by Oliver Jensen in American Heritage. Bibliography of Frick articles, 1920-1929. "Pitt Selects Frick Arts Director, Outlines Plans", Pittsburgh Post-Gazette.
- Furniture [Part I], 161 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 161)
  Notable Item: Undated, unlabeled photographs of 1700s furniture.
- Furniture [Part II], 162 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 162)
  Notable Items: Many postcards featuring furniture. The History behind the English and French Periods of Furniture [poster], Research Bureau for Retail Training, University of Pittsburgh, February 1942, W. Sobotka.
- Glass and Glassware, 163 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 163)
- Goldsmithing, 164 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 164)
- Graphic Arts, 165 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 165)
- Greece, 166; Contains one item: "The Lost Atlantis", 1971, Smithsonian Magazine. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 166)
- Greeting Cards, 167 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 167)
- Heraldry, 168 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 168)
- Historic Houses, 169; Chiefly brochures and pamphlets relating to specific houses. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 169)
- Historic Preservation -- Bibliographies, 170 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 170)
- Illumination of Books and Manuscripts, 171 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 171)
- Illustration of Books, 172 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 172)
- Index of American Design, 173 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 173)
- Indians of North America, 174 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 174)
- Indians of Mexico, 175 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 175)
- India, 176; Contains one item: "Scenes from an India in Ferment" by Dard Hunter, New York Times Magazine, May 15, 1938. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 176)
- Industrial Design, 177 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 177)
- Interior Decoration [Interior Design], 178 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 178)
- International Book Society, 179 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 179)
- International Center of Medieval Art, 180; Contains one item: Annual Meeting Agenda and letter, January 1970. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 180)
- International Exchange Program, 181 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 181)
- Ironwork, 182 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 182)
  Notable Item: Jean Lamour: Serrurier du roi Stanislas, a Nancy, par Charles Cournault. 1886, J.Rouam, Editeur.
- Italy, 183 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 183)
- Ivories, 184 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 184)
- Jade, 185; Contains one item: Pamphlet on Chinese Jade, n.d. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 185)
- Jewelry, 186 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 186)
- Lace and Lace Making, 187 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 187)
- Landscape Gardening, 188 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 188)
- Landscape Painting, 189 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 189)
- Language and Languages, 190 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 190)
  Contains two items: Notes on Far Eastern Studies in America, June 1937, American Council of Learned Societies, Washington, D.C., and a pocket calendar for the year 1938, compliments of J. J. Augustin, 30 Irving Place, New York City.
- Leather work, 191; Contains one item: Miniature pamphlet, "The Care of Leather", pub. LeatherVita, n.d. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 191)
- Libraries [Part I], 192 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 192)
- Libraries [Part II], 193 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 193)
  Notable Items: ACRL & SLA Joint Metting, Fall 1965, at Frick Fine Arts Building, various event handouts. Arts Information International, founded in 1970, based in Hillman Library, various information. Hunt Botanical Library, various pamphlets including dedication folio from 1961.
- Library Associations, 194; Contains one item: ASIS (American Society for Information Science) mailing packet, c.1969. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 194)
- Lithography, 195 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 195)
- Manuscripts, 196 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 196)
  Contains various prospectus for manuscript fasimiles. Notably, contains the Prospectus of the Reproduction from the Diary of Mido Kampaku, The Imperial Treasure.
- Manuscripts: Rous roll & Earls of Warwick, 197 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 197)
- Maps, 198 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 198)
  Notable Item: Relief Panorama of the Rhine, Verlag von Hoursch & Bechstedt, Koln a. Rh. No. 11
- Masks, 199 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 199)
- Medals, 200 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 200)
- Medicine, 201 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 201)
- Metal Work, 202 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 202)
- Mexico, 203; Contains one item: Mexico tourist guide, 1941. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 203)
- Mobiles, 204 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 204)
- Mosaics, 205 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 205)
  Notable items include: Die Pyramide, Mosaik, pub. Berlin, 1929-30. Mosaics, Grand Canal S. Gregorio, 195, Venise, Erede D.'A. Salviati & Co., n.d.
- Moving Pictures, 206 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 206)
- Mural Painting and Decoration, 207 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 207)
- Museum and Conservation Training, 208 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 208)
- Museums and Galleries - General Information [Part I], 209 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 209)
- Museums and Galleries - General Information [Part II], 210 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 210)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - A-B, 211 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 211)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - C [Part I], 212 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 212)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - C [Part II], 213 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 213)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - D-E, 214 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 214)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - F-M, 215 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 215)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - New York City [Part I], 216 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 216)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - New York City [Part II], 217 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 217)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - N-P, 218 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 218)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - R, 219 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 219)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - S, 220 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 220)
  Notable Items: Decorations and Trophies, Colonel Charles A. Lindbergh, Missouri Historical Society. Museum of Fine Arts Handbook, Springfield, Mass., 1958.
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - T-Z, 221 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 221)
- Museums and Galleries - Domestic - Washington, D.C., 222 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 222)
- Museums and Galleries - Foreign - A-D, 223 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 223)
- Museums and Galleries - Foreign - England, 224 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 224)
- Museums and Galleries - Foreign - E-M, 225 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 225)
- Museums and Galleries - Foreign - N-Z, 226 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 226)
- Music, 227 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 227)
- Mythology, 228 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 4, Folder 228)
- National Council on the Arts, 229; Contains one item: Report from the first five years, 1966-1970. (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 229)
- Needlework, 230 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 230)
- Negro in Art, 231 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 231)
- New York (City), 232 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 232)
- Nordenfalk, Carl, 233; Contains one item: Obituary of Carl Nordenfalk. Professor at Pitt in Fine Arts during 1970s. (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 233)
- Numismatics, 234 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 234)
- Occupational Therapy, 235 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 235)
- Painting, 236 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 236)
- Painting, American, 237 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 237)
- Painting, Chinese, 238 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 238)
- Painting, Danish, 239 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 239)
- Painting, French, 240 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 240)
- Painting, German-Hungarian, 241 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 241)
- Painting, Indian, Italian, Japanese, 242 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 242)
- Painting, Modern, 243 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 243)
- Painting, Oriental, 244; Contains one item: Newspaper clipping, "Eastern Art" (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 244)
- Painting, Russian, Spanish, 245 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 245)
- Paleontology, 246; Contains one item: "The Cave that Looks back on America 20,000 years ago" news clipping (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 246)
- Paper, 247 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 247)
- Parks and Gardens, 248 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 248)
- Pennsylvania -- Art and Artists, 249 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 249)
- Pennsylvania -- Cities, 250 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 250)
- Pennsylvania -- General and Historical, 251 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 251)
- Pewter, 252 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 252)
- Photographers, 253 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 253)
- Photography, 254 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 254)
- Picture Frames and Framing, 255 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 255)
- Pittsburgh -- Architecture [Part I], 256 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 256)
- Pittsburgh -- Architecture [Part II], 257 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 257)
- Pittsburgh -- Architecture -- Market Square, 258; Original folder label: Article on Market Square and its development by James Van Trump, March-April 1971. (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 258)
- Pittsburgh -- Art [Part I], 259 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 259)
- Pittsburgh -- Art [Part II], 260 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 260)
- Pittsburgh -- Bicentennial, 1958-1959, 261 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 261)
- Pittsburgh -- Carnegie Institute -- Carnegie Museum and Library, 262 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 262)
- Pittsburgh -- Carnegie Museum of Art -- Exhibitions A-Z, 263 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 263)
- Pittsburgh -- Carnegie Museum of Art -- General, 264 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 264)
- Pittsburgh -- Carnegie Museum of Art -- International Exhibitions, 265 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 265)
- Pittsburgh -- Churches, 266 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 266)
- Pittsburgh -- Clayton, 267 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 267)
- Pittsburgh -- History, 268 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 268)
- Pittsburgh -- History and Landmarks Museum, 269 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 269)
- Pittsburgh -- Frick Art Museum, 270 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 270)
- Pittsburgh -- Pittsburgh Center for the Arts, 271 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 271)
- Pittsburgh -- Pittsburgh Filmmakers, 272 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 272)
- Pittsburgh -- Pittsburgh Foundation, 273 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 273)
- Pittsburgh -- Sculpture, 274 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 274)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh, 275 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 275)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Libraries, 276 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 276)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Department of Fine Arts -- Articles by Faculty, 277 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 277)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Department of Fine Arts -- Articles about faculty and exhibit reviews, 278 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 278)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Frick Fine Arts Building, 279 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 279)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Frick Fine Arts Building -- Exhibits, 280 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 280)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Frick Fine Arts Building -- History, 281 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 281)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- Nationality Rooms, 282 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 282)
- Pittsburgh -- University of Pittsburgh -- University Art Gallery, 283 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 1, Folder 283)
- Plants in Art, 284 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 284)
- Poland, 285 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 285)
- Portraits, 286 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 286)
- Postage Stamps, 287 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 287)
- Posters, 288 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 288)
- Pottery, 289 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 289)
- Pottery -- Exhibitions, 290 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 290)
- Pottery -- Technique, 291 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 291)
- Print Council of America, 292 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 292)
- Printing -- General and Catalogs, 293 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 293)
- Printing -- History, 294 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 294)
- Printing -- Practical Techniques, 295 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 295)
- Printing -- Private Presses, 296 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 296)
- Printing -- Typefaces, Printers' Marks, etc., 297 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 297)
- Prints, 298 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 298)
- Prints -- Catalogs, 299 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 299)
- Prints -- Engravings, 300 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 300)
- Puppetry, 301 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 301)
- Railroads, 302 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 302)
- Romania, 303 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 303)
- Rugs, 304 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 304)
- Scientific Expeditions, 305 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 305)
- Sculpture, 306 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 306)
- Sculpture -- A-Z, 307 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 307)
- Sculpture -- Modern -- 20th Century, 308 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 308)
- Selma Burke Art Center, 309 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 309)
- Serigraphy, 310 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 310)
- Shakers, 311 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 311)
- Ships, 312 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 312)
- Silversmithing, 313 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 313)
- Snuffboxes, 314 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 314)
- Spain, 315 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 315)
- Sports in Art, 316 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 316)
- Stained Glass, 317 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 317)
- Still Life, 318 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 318)
- Swedes in Ameica, 319 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 319)
- Symbolism, 320 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 320)
- Tapestry, 321 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 321)
- Television, 322 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 322)
- Terra Cotta, 323 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 323)
- Textiles, 324 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 324)
- Theater, 325 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 325)
- Typography, 326 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 326)
- Uniforms -- Military, 327 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 327)
- United Nations, 328 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 328)
- United States -- History, 329 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 329)
- United States -- Treasury Department Works Progress Administration, 330 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 330)
- Universities and Colleges, 331 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 331)
- Vase Painting, 332 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 332)
- Video Art, 333 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 333)
- Wallpaper, 334 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 334)
- War in Art, 335 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 335)
- Washington, D.C., 336 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 336)
- Wax Portraits, 337 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 337)
- Weaving, 338 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 338)
- Who's Who A-Z Biography, 339 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 339)
- Women as Artists [Female Artists], 340 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 340)
- Woodwork, 341 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 341)
- Zen, 342 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 342)
- Zodiac, 343 (File-cabinet 2, Drawer 2, Folder 343)